<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_1696862840" name="Variety and Rebalance Overhaul" description="[h1] Variety and Rebalance Overhaul (VRO)[/h1] &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Current Version: 1.96&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Consider it SEMI-COMPATIBLE with 3.0 beta, no new weapons or ships are rebalanced, some weapon effects may look outdated.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;VRO 2.0 will be released with X4 patch 3.0.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;TL;DR&#13;&#10;This mod updates every single ship, weapon and shield to bring variety to the game and make the combat less arcady. All weapons now have different behaviors and sounds, there is no more MK system, most L weapons have new GFX. Ships are more survivable, larger ships are much less maneuverable. Shields do not have regen delay, now its more hard to kill L ship on your own.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10; [url=https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/305] LINK TO NEXUS if you need one[/url] &#13;&#10; [url=https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QR5njiXz1Bs&amp;list=PL7trGC1vz4uit-v5ruznRgb2eQhxU1Yqe] Some videos in this channel[/url] &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;For not so lazy people:&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Why?[/b] &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[spoiler] I liked the game at first, after some time tough was bored by how plain combat and ships were, every weapon looked and worked alike, every ship had only slight difference. But then I found a mod Shield and Weapon Overhaul that made game much more enjoyable, I was intrigued how many can be changed by simple xml edit. So, after Shield and Weapon Overhaul mod was abandoned I decided to make my own but with more whistles and blowers, hope you will like it.&#13;&#10;[/spoiler] &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Movement[/b] &#13;&#10;THERE IS NO BOOST (will be back in 2.0), this is a big boon to AI and makes combat more engaging. Fighters and some M ships are faster to compensate, also, travel speed was boosted (use it where you used boost before). Ships, especially larger ones) are less maneuverable, do not except F1 speeds from heavy fighters and scout high maneuverability from frigates. All L and XL ships now behave if they are really big ships.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Ships[/b] &#13;&#10;Every faction is a bit different in regards what they prefer:&#13;&#10;Argons love their behemoths and heavy fighters.&#13;&#10;Paranids focus on small ships that have much better shields than other races, while their Odysseys and Nemesis are just glass cannons.&#13;&#10;Teladi have quite beafy L and XL ships, but theirs Ospreys and Peregrins are force to reckon with. Also, most ships with docks can carry much more drones that are cheaper than using fighters. Profitsss.&#13;&#10;All docking was redone to make sense with difference in ships variants as well. L ships now have 60km radar, XL – 80km.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Durability/Shields[/b] &#13;&#10;All HP of ships is boosted and rebalanced from ground up, as well as shields now have 0 delay in recharge that makes it harder to kill big ships with smaller ones (due to “Shield Armor”, see below). Combat now takes more time.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Weapons/”Shield Armor”[/b] &#13;&#10;[b]THERE ARE NO MORE MKs.[/b]  Every weapon is usable and different.&#13;&#10;I tried to give every weapon its own role and distinctive behavior with noticeable difference between S, M and L guns. Also, weapons are now separated a bit as those that are good against large ships and those that are not, this is done with an “Shield Armor” concept – heavy weapons are more inaccurate with low ROF but have additional shield damage to negate high passive regen of capital ships, Plasma cannons, Ion guns, Autocannons will help you to combat large beasts. All ranges are boosted, Capital ships combat is around 15-20 km, while some heavy fighter weapons reach 9km.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Please provide your feedback as balance may still be a bit wacky, as I was not able the test everything on my own. Especially large weapon dps.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Compatibility:[/b] &#13;&#10;- For game Version 2.6&#13;&#10;- This mod WILL OVERWRITE any other changes to ships, weapons or shield parameters from any mod if loaded after them (in alphabetic order) so if you want to run it alongside FOCW you are free to do so.&#13;&#10;- Not sure if compatible with old saves due to changes in carry capacities of the ships. You can try :)&#13;&#10;- Works fine with faction fix mod&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Recommended mods:[/b] &#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?section=collections&amp;appid=392160]Faction War/Economy Enhancer for obvious reasons[/url] &#13;&#10;[url=https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/80]NoSuperHighways – not mandatory but highways neglect any speed difference between S and M ships, while also decreasing boons to travels speeds in the mod.[/url] &#13;&#10;[url=https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?f=181&amp;t=415301]FireFx mod[/url]  - please use [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1699793598]the patch[/url] for it to work properly &#13;&#10;[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1700645587]Better Kill Credit[/url] &#13;&#10;[url=https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/68]Boarding Pod Crews[/url] &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Plans for future:[/b] &#13;&#10;- Add new ships and variants for existing ships.&#13;&#10;- Give each ship unique internal shield generator in addition to normal ones to even more diversify them. - done in VRO 2.0&#13;&#10;- Update weapon graphics, impacts and projectiles mostly.&#13;&#10;- Introduce more weapons to the game. - prtially done in VRO 2.0&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b] Thanks to:[/b] &#13;&#10;Egosoft&#13;&#10;mewosmith for helping and supporting me&#13;&#10;AngEviL for creating Shield and Weapon Overhaul mod that inspired me&#13;&#10;Chirumiru ShiRoz for letting me use some of his Stellaris mod sounds; check it out if you play stellaris.&#13;&#10;Ego modding discord channel for providing great insight into how things work&#13;&#10;PaPaYa for French translation!&#13;&#10;RoverTX for improvements to some ships." author="Shuul" version="200" date="2019-12-14" save="1" enabled="1" sync="false" lastupdate="1573254855">
  <!-- <text language="49" name="Variety and Rebalance Overhaul" description="This mods brings full rebalanse of Ships, Engines and Shields. Weapons are are fully redone, now without mk system, with new sound effects for most and GFX for few. Makes game less arcady, combat a bit more deadly, engagement ranges larger, large ships stronger." author="Shuul" />
	<text language="7" name="Variety and Rebalance Overhaul" description="This mods brings full rebalanse of Ships, Engines and Shields. Weapons are are fully redone, now without mk system, with new sound effects for most and GFX for few. Makes game less arcady, combat a bit more deadly, engagement ranges larger, large ships stronger." author="Shuul" />
	<text language="44" name="Variety and Rebalance Overhaul" description="This mods brings full rebalanse of Ships, Engines and Shields. Weapons are are fully redone, now without mk system, with new sound effects for most and GFX for few. Makes game less arcady, combat a bit more deadly, engagement ranges larger, large ships stronger." author="Shuul" /> -->
</content>
