<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<content id="ws_1696862840" name="Variety and Rebalance Overhaul" description="Current Version: 2.1.4 FOR 3.1 GAME AND SPLIT DLC ( does not work without DLC, trying to fix)&#13;&#10;NEXUS LINK https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/305&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;MOD REQUIRES NEW GAME (vanilla saves won't work) AND CANNOT BE SAFELY DEACTIVATED &#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]TL;DR[/b]&#13;&#10;VRO overhauls the way game plays by changing the parameters of every ship, weapon, engine, shield and many other tweaks to make the game more varied, enjoyable and less player-centric and arcady.&#13;&#10;All weapons have new behaviour, sounds, effects and are now useful in different situations. Added more weapons. Ranges are increased, weapon sizes are more distinct.&#13;&#10;Missiles are completely redone, by bringing back missiles form previous X titles and limiting missile classes to different sizes of launchers.&#13;&#10;Ship classes are more distinct, L,XL ships are more powerful, added few new ships. Carriers and Resupply ships are more useful in their intended role.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]SCOPE[/b]&#13;&#10;VRO will not change drastically economics or politics of the game, though some changes may be done to e.g. ship/weapon prices as they connect directly to the combat balance.&#13;&#10;New weapons, ships, general combat overhaul is the focus of the VRO. There is a list of recommended mods to use alongside VRO.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]BE WARNED / DISCLAMER[/b]&#13;&#10;VRO makes game a bit more difficult, there may be no “best ship” in the game as I strived for balance, early game may be more dangerous while you are flying starting ship, so avoid direct combat if you are not certain you can win. Remember to rely more on support of your other ships in combat.&#13;&#10;ALSO, Xenons may be more of a threat now, so, if you are very unlucky and factions fail to oppose them, they can really take of over the universe, if given enough time, i suggest to monitor the situation in galaxy more closely then in vanilla and try to help factions if needed.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]IMPORTANT NOTE[/b]&#13;&#10;This mod was built with the below mods in mind, so they are STRONGLY recommended, although not mandatory.&#13;&#10;Faction War/Economy Enhancer - Makes some necessary changes to factions and ship behaviors, not mandatory mod. https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?f=181&amp;t=413122 &#13;&#10; NoSuperHighways - makes game to feel bigger, closer to X3 and gives the opportunity to balance S,M and L,XL ships properly as highways are messing with that. https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/80&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Detailed description of upcoming VRO 2.0 (Mostly major changes compared to vanilla):&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Ships Overhaul[/b]&#13;&#10;- Ships in general are faster, including travel speeds&#13;&#10;- Engines are rebalanced for their role (allround/travel/combat)&#13;&#10;- All ships now have built-in shield generator that are mostly responsible for shield regen&#13;&#10;- Shields do not have regen delay&#13;&#10;- Boost was changed to last longer but be more of a combat boost than travel-drive replacement (no instant boosting)&#13;&#10;- S ships have a bit more varied maneuverability, M, L and XL ships are more clunky and less maneuverable&#13;&#10;- S ships are now divided more into Interceptor, Fighter and Heavy fighter roles.&#13;&#10;- L and XL ships are now true capital ships, more survivable, expensive and dangerous&#13;&#10;- Some ships have changed turret loadouts (mostly tealdies)&#13;&#10;- Argons tend to focus on L ships/heavy fighters, tealdi on M/XL ships, Paranids on fighters and their destroyers&#13;&#10;- New Xenon missile destroyer V, some other Xenon ships have new weapons and missiles&#13;&#10;- Vanilla frigates were designated as corvettes&#13;&#10;- Frigates are now new large ship class, something between corvette and destroyer. They have good forward firepower and good anti-fighter turret coverage, though no L turrets.&#13;&#10;- Introduced new Centaur frigate (model form X3) for argon, (centaur has temporary collision mesh, as due to the bug with 3.0 beta its sometimes impossible to import custom collision meshes)&#13;&#10;- Introduced new Shrike frigate for Teladi, repurposed commercial ship to serve as light carrier (yes, you can resupply and repair fighters in it)&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Weapons/Turrets Overhaul[/b]&#13;&#10;- No more MK1/2 system, a lot of new weapons were added&#13;&#10;- Ranges of engagement are now different, S weapons up to 5km, M weapons/turrets up to 9 km, L weapons/turrets up to 20 km&#13;&#10;- All S and M weapons (front guns) are now divided into LIGHT and HEAVY, different ships have different hardpoints (e.g. Falcon has 2 LIGHT, while Nova has 1 LIGHT and 1 LIGHT/HEAVY and Perseus has 2 LIGHT/HEAVY and Guilemont has 1 HEAVY)&#13;&#10;- All vanilla weapons/turrets are rebalanced/replaced to have their own niche and use.&#13;&#10;- All weapons names/description updated&#13;&#10;- Weapons now have different amount of damage vs hull and vs shield. Use HEAVY weapons with additional shield damage to combat high shield regen values of the larger ships&#13;&#10;- L turrets and weapons are designed to be true capital weapons, with high range and damage, while inaccurate and with low efficiency against S ships&#13;&#10;- Most weapons with “Plasma” in the name have additional damage against components&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Missiles overhaul[/b]&#13;&#10;- All vanilla missiles are removed (may still be present in tutorial etc)&#13;&#10;- Missiles are now divided into classes - Light, Medium, Heavy, Torpedo, Cruise&#13;&#10;- S launchers and M missile turrets are limited to Light and Medium missiles&#13;&#10;- M launchers and L missile turrets are limited to Medium and Heavy missiles&#13;&#10;- Dumbfire and Tracking launchers can be fitted only in LIGHT weapon hardpoints, Torpedo launchers can be fitted only in HEAVY hardpoints&#13;&#10;- Cruise missiles can be used only with L Cruise turret&#13;&#10;- All ship missile capacities are redone&#13;&#10;- All missiles have a detailed encyclopedia entry with the following abbreviations:&#13;&#10;L - light&#13;&#10;M - medium&#13;&#10;H - heavy&#13;&#10;D - dumbfire&#13;&#10;G - guided&#13;&#10;T - torpedo&#13;&#10;CR - cruise&#13;&#10;HEAT, LOCK, SMART - missile lock mechanic&#13;&#10;AOE/high AOE, SWARM - additional characteristics&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Additional Tweaks to game[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;- Khaak installations now destructible, previously it lled to whole fleets stranding trying to kill them&#13;&#10;- Shield components are now not lost/destroyed during bail-out, boarding.&#13;&#10;- Auxiliary and Carrier storages are increased to make them more efficient in their support role&#13;&#10;- L freighters cargo hold increased by 25% to make them more competitive to M freighters&#13;&#10;- Defense modules HP increased by x4, with new weapon balance old values were quite small&#13;&#10;- Prices of heavy fighters, destroyers and carriers are increased&#13;&#10;- L radar range is 60km, XL - 80km&#13;&#10;- Replaced map icons for scouts, heavy fighters, bombers/gunships, defense drones, battleships, added icon for new frigates class&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Recommended mods:[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?f=181&amp;t=421227 Recycle Ships and Stations (and his other mods)&#13;&#10;https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/136 Getting Paid&#13;&#10;https://www.nexusmods.com/x4foundations/mods/85 Disabled encounters - remove random spawned ships&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;You can use other mods that change music, logos, some minor tweaks to game mechanics that do not directly change weapons or ships, they should be OK in general.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Recommended mods, that can influence performance:[/b]&#13;&#10;https://forum.egosoft.com/viewtopic.php?f=181&amp;t=419641 XR Ship Pack - when he will release VRO patch that is in the works&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;[b]Compatibility:[/b]&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;Merged-in mods (no need to install separately):&#13;&#10;Faction battleships - adds battleships to factions based on Auxiliary ships hulls&#13;&#10;Rovers Improved XXXX mods - most of them are either part of VRO or conflict with it.&#13;&#10;&#13;&#10;If you would like to support me, here is my Patreon https://www.patreon.com/shuul" author="Shuul" version="215" date="2020-04-21" save="1" enabled="1" sync="false" lastupdate="1587405296">
</content>
